# Chi Calvin Nguyen . Jarvis Consulting

I am a dedicated team player who is inquisitive, punctual, and goes by the book. I recently graduated with an Ontario College Advanced Diploma from the Computer Programming & Analysis program at George Brown College. During my time at George Brown, I've learned technologies such as React, Node.js, Angular, MongoDB, Spring, and ASP.NET by building projects like a front-end application that connects to an open-source weather API or full-stack applications where we built both the front and backend while following Agile project management methodology. I've also gained other skills outside George Brown that are crucial to a workplace. My ability to communicate and act as a team player established itself throughout my time as a bartender/server. I worked in a rough fast-paced environment that required me to be on my toes, give the best possible service to customers, and work within a tight-knit team. I am quite a hobbyist with hobbies such as brewing beer, where I experiment with recipes to get the best possible batch, which is why I also like tech because I constantly learn, test, and create software. Overall, I'm hoping for an opportunity in the software development industry where I can prove myself as a team member.

#### Skills

Proficient: JavaScript, Angular/React, NodeJS, Git, RDBMS/SQL

Competent: Java, Spring, Docker, Python, Agile/Scrum, REST APIs, HTML/CSS

Familiar: Linux/Bash, C#, ASP.NET, PHP, Swift

## **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/Jarvis-Consulting-Group/jarvis\_data\_eng-C-CalvinNguyen

Linux Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Collects the hardware specifications and usage for the Linux nodes within a cluster and stores this data inside the database. Docker manages a container running the PostgreSQL database, and this container is set up using a Bash script (psql\_docker.sh). The other Bash scripts (hardware\_info.sh and hardware\_usage.sh) collect and store the data in the database using Linux commands like lscpu, vmstat, and psql. Finally, a cron job schedules the script's execution every minute and stores the data in the PostgreSQL database within the Docker container.

#### **Highlighted Projects**

Ionic/Angular Mobile Music Player Application & Streaming System [GitHub]: Plays local audio files on Android mobile devices, and the app can also create an account to upload and stream files from the backend server/system. MongoDB stores account information once an account is registered. The front-end/client-side mobile application uses Angular/(Ionic); it can read local audio files, stores their metadata into an SQLite local storage, play these files, and connect to the backend server once authenticated. The NodeJS backend server allows users to create accounts, upload audio files onto the server, and stream it back to the user.

**Spring Cookbook App** [GitHub]: Allows users to create, manage, search, share, and favorite recipes on the application. Includes other features like planning a meal schedule or creating a shopping list from the ingredient's checklist in a recipe. The project uses Spring for the backend controllers and services, Thymeleaf for the front-end templating engine in HTML/CSS files, and H2 Database that is integrated into Spring automatically through a SQL file.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2023-present): I joined as a Junior Software Developer to consult and aid in developing Jarvis' client's software solutions. To do this, I learned new technologies while working on projects at Jarvis in an Agile/Scrum environment where there were daily scrum meetings in the morning to discuss project progress and sprint meetings every two weeks. The technologies learned at Jarvis are specially selected as they are common within the professional tech workplace environment, and an example of these technologies are Linux, SQL, Java, Spring, etc.

Bartender/Server, Hazel's Diner (2018-2020): Worked as a team in a fast-paced environment where communication with coworkers and customers was the key to fulfilling orders and providing excellent service within a given time frame. Responsibilities of the position included bussing food, mixing drinks, cleaning tables, managing dishwashers, and other tasks. I gained certifications such as Smart Serve and First Aid for the position. I learned more about the restaurant's workflow when working alongside the team, and this diversified my responsibilities within the restaurant.

# Education

George Brown College (2019-2022), Ontario College Advanced Diploma, T127 Computer Programmer Analyst - School of Computer Technology - Dean's List (2019-2022): Was on the Dean's list by achieving a term GPA above 3.5 - GPA: 3.83/4.0

### Miscellaneous

- Co-operative games like board games or online multiplayer video games.
- Brewing beer (Pale ales, IPAs, Stouts)
- Leisure ice skating, watching hockey (on TV or in-person) and playing street hockey or pickup hockey (shinny).